# **AKSHAY SINHA**

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/AKSHAY-SINHA-15A54A178/

CELL: 4167050684 | EMAIL: AKSHAY92CA@GMAIL.COM | GITHUB | KAGGLE

## **PROFILE**

Motivated, teamwork-oriented, and responsible Data Analyst with experience in increasing comprehension of reports and presentations by the average professional. Highly educated, possessing Diploma in Business Administration in Finance and professional certification in Data Analysis. Bilingual in English and Hindi with intermediate understanding of Urdu and Punjabi.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: 'R', SQL, Python

Libraries: tidyverse, dyplr, ggplot2, lubridate, tibble

Data Management: Database Design & Management, Data Quality Assessment, Data Analysis, Pattern & Trend

Identification, Visualization of Data Insights

Other: Tableau, HTML, CSS, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Suite

#### **PROJECTS**

Cyclistic Bike Share Program – Link

- Used 'R' to handle multiple large data frames
- Cleaned, process and analyzed data frames using libraries like tidyverse, and lubridate in 'R'
- Used library applot2 for data visualization
- Made recommendations to the company about next steps for growth in membership

Web Development - Project 1 & Project 2

- Converted professional designs to HTML & CSS with layout models like Flexbox
- Implemented responsive designs that work across mobile and desktop devices
- Used best practices for modern web development and website accessibility requirements

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Films & Commercials

Executed concepts into scenes under short deadlines

DOP, Camera Operator, 1st & 2nd Camera Assistant

Mar 2018 – April 2021

Various Location

- Managed and coached new hires on the various equipment used on a shoot
- Operated various different camera systems and lens for tv shows and commercials
- Maintained a flexible work ethic to support evolving production needs

# **Cosmos Financial Group Inc.**

Mississauga

Administrative Assistant

June 2017 - September 2018

- Generated reports and presentations for monthly and quarterly review
- Addressed client's policy concerns through data visualization and data manipulation
- Increased policy adherence by 15% by maintaining strong communication channel with clients

#### **Nike Corporation**

Scarborough

Aug 2016 - Mar 2017

Health and Safety Specialist

- Enforced safety regulations across the warehouse which cut down on accident by 37%
- Optimized vendor information catalog to ensure all vendors on the property had proper training, certificates and licenses
- Increase battery changing area capacity by 200% by implementing new schematics
- Redesigned high traffic areas to bring monthly forklift accidents from 4-5 to 0
- Created employee data sheets and pivot tables for cross checking licenses, permits and validations

Bank of Nova Scotia Mississauga

Customer Service Representative – Team Leader

Nov 2012 - July 2016

- Earned vault code privileges and directed branch cash holdings for day to day transactions
- Trained team members in day to day banking operations
- Advised customers on various financial opportunities
- Organized shipment of incoming and outgoing cash shipments, bank drafts, money orders etc.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Coursera - Online

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate 04/2021 – 07/2021

**Toronto Film School - Toronto** 

Film Production 06/2017-12/2018

**Canadian Securities Institute - Toronto** 

Investment Funds in Canada 06/2015

Juno College - Toronto

Web Development 08/2019 – 10/2019

Sheridan College - Oakville

Business Administration in Finance 01/2012-06/2016